I am a senior software engineer with a deep knownledge on designing and implementing large scale Web solutions. I like to manage complex and challenging software engineering projects, with a focus on the results, the user-experience and on matching deadlines.

I have participated to grow a consulting company from 2 to 60 people, created one of the best Web application framework for the JVM, and helped many prestigious companies to evolve their software engineering practices.

Skills

Software architecture: Building large scale, distributed, resilient, continuously deployed Web architecture solutions.

Programming languages: Java, Scala, JavaScript & Rust.

Web development: HTML, JavaScript & CSS - Realtime Web applications - Interface design.

Mobile development: Web based or native mobile application development (on both Android and iOS).

Project management: Leading development team, matching deadline, understanding client needs (including with international and distributed project teams).

Work experience

Co-founder at Zengularity

2004 - Present

I have co-founded the company and participated to grow it to more than 60 people. I have held many responsabilities from managing the company, hiring and coaching teams, managing software projects. I have also conducted numerous consulting missions for some prestigious clients.

Some projects I conducted at Zengularity include:

- LCL (Bank): Designed, implemented and managed a brand new Java development framework for the core banking applications.
- ☐ **LinkedIn:** Deployment of Play as development framework for the front-end team.

prismic.io: Challenged CMS with a brand new solution based on a versioned content store, an advanced content management application and a set of Web API to consume and display the content anywhere.

Lead developer at Play framework

2008 - 2012

I have created the Play framework open source project, and led the development team until its integration to the Typesafe stack.

It is today one of the major Web development framework for the JVM (supporting both the Java and Scala programming languages), and it is used as Web development framework by many companies such as LinkedIn, Apple, Klout, Gilt, The Guardian, etc.

I gave several public talks about Play at JavaOne, JavaZone and Devoxx conferences.

Software engineer at INRIA

2002 - 2004

Software engineer for the ECOO research team. I have worked on implementing algorithms and proof of concept. I have participated to some INRIA, Bull, France-télécom consortium projects. I was also assistant teacher for some Java courses.

Internship at SQLI

2001 (6 months)

I have worked on some Website and Web applications development.

Formal education

2002 Master at University of Nancy (France).

1998 Baccalauréat (French secondary school diploma).